MOHAN KRISHNA CHADRAM

Parsippany, New Jersey | mohankrishna.chadram@gmail.com | (405)-762-3053 https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohanchadram

SUMMARY

IT Business Analyst with 6+ years of experience in the space of Technology and Business Processes. I am expertise working with cross-functional teams in the software development, model workflows, supporting business solutions and analyzing business operations. Experienced in managing various aspects of Project life cycle including requirements gathering, scope, milestones, requirements analysis, risk management, and GAP analysis.

I am a certified *Scrum Master* and *Product Manager* who can lead, schedule, plan and facilitate continuous Business process improvement events. Data Science enthusiast who can apply known analytical skills in Data Analysis and visualization in the area of Big data and Machine Learning to add value to Business Decision making.

SKILLS:

- *Programming*: Python, SQL, Soap Webservices, SAS, PL/SQL, Java.
- Data Analysis: Tableau, Cognos, Informatica Data Quality & MDM.
- Workflows: ITSM, JIRA, GitHub, HP ALM.
- Database management/IDEs: Oracle, Teradata, SQL Server, SAS Enterprise Guide, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook.
- *Cybersecurity*: Identity and Access Management (IAM); Governance, Risk & Compliance (GRC RSAM).
- Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) Methodologies: Agile (Scrum), Lean, Waterfall.

Certifications: Scrum Master, Product Manager & Owner, ITIL, Six Sigma (Green Belt)

EXPERIENCE

Business Analyst

Client: Blue Cross Blue Shield Employer: Natsoft Corporation Project: Claims Member Portal Newark, NJ Apr 2020 - Till Date

The aim of Claims Member Portal Team is to analyze, understand and translate business needs into business/technical requirements. Lead and coordinates teams of other functional departments to ensure alignment of technical solutions with business requirements for medium to complex issues (quantity and magnitude). Manage the deployment of tools and methodologies (e.g. SIPOC) to identify process and operational efficiencies in business current and future state models to optimize business value.

Responsibilities:

- Facilitate Change & Data Management across entire process from Project conceptualization to Testing through Project Delivery, Software Development and Implementation in diverse Business and Technical Environments.
- Worked on Business forecasting, segmentation analysis and Data mining and prepared management reports defining the problem.

- Performed data analysis and processed third party spending data into maneuverable deliverables within specific format with Excel macros and python libraries such as NumPy and matplotlib.
- Prepared a claim data for risk adjustment by extracting, cleaning, and merging from different tables using SQL.
- Worked on data that was a combination of unstructured and structured data from multiple sources and automated the cleaning using Python scripts.
- Developed SQL programs to create a customized Risk Adjustment Processing System (RAPS) file and a customized RAPS return integration for clients based on client request.
- Create, document and review of business/Functional Requirement Documents/Traceability Matrix (BRD, FRD, RTM) and System Requirement Specifications (SRS) through Business use cases and data mapping to control numerous artifacts produced by Teams across the deliverables.
- Gather & identify API requirements for many REST web-services that support JSON, which were used company-wide for various applications and web portals.
- Work with solutions/delivery teams to implement data quality processes during acquisition, ETL, and delivery stages for Business Intelligence solutions and changes to Data Warehouses.
- Execution of Runbook and gathering various requirements that include Functional Technical System to create the runbook.

Business Analyst

Client: J P Morgan Chase

Employer: Tata Consultancy Services

Project: Document Management (Banking)

Columbus, OH

Jan 2018 - Mar 2020

The goal of CCB - Document Management Project is to provide maintenance/enhancements, integrations of modules and testing. Image Archive and Retrieval project provides services to search and retrieve documents from various archives of the firm, System Testing, Integration Testing, Regression Testing and User Acceptance Testing for the Servicing and Default applications. Image Archive and Retrieval project has a web portal to search and retrieve any document from various archives like IBM OnDemand, FileNet P8 and ETA archives. The web portal also allows the users to modify a document and upload to the archive, print the documents, fax and mail the documents. The project goal is to make enhancements to the web portal to make users access the documents easily.

Responsibilities:

- Facilitate implementation of new functional & non-functional requirements.
- Lead the Scrum Team's Product Backlog grooming, User Story development and Sprint prioritization.
- Coordinate across cross LOB's product owners, project managers, stakeholders and subject matter experts (SMEs) as the lead Business Analyst.
- Involved in all phases of data mining; data collection, data cleaning, developing models, validation, visualization and performed Gap analysis.
- Articulate default customers profiles along with reports using Python and Tableau to generate analytical results and strategic implications to senior management for strategic decision making.
- Performed Data cleansing and manipulations using Python scripts to derive the customer query addressable with decreased the time for solving the query.
- Work with developers, user experience designers, subject matter experts, legal and compliance teams to obtain a well-rounded understanding of what is being asked for and our ability to deliver it within the constraints of our banking environment.
- Assesses potential impacts and changes to our core UIs, middleware services and Frameworks.
- Collaborated with other functional teams across the Risk and Non-Risk groups to use standard methodologies and ensure a positive customer experience throughout the customer journey.
- Engaged in creation of project workflows, Demos, User guides, support manuals for Technology Teams through Atlassian Confluence and JIRA.

Business Analyst

Client: J P Morgan Chase

Employer: Tata Consultancy Services

Employer: Axistech INC

Project: Identity and Access Management (Cybersecurity)

Columbus, OH May 2017 - Jan 2018 Jun 2016 - May 2017

I am member of the Chase CCB (Consumer & Community Banking) Access Uplift - Identity & Access Management Team. Responsible to perform end-to-end information systems compliance testing that included assessing risk and formal reporting of risk internal and external to the enterprise. Compliance activities include Sarbanes-Oxley compliance, operational audits, Information Technology audits, internal audits, external audits, business analysis and requirements gathering.

Responsibilities:

- Develop and maintain the Identity and Access Management Architecture and standards.
- Worked closely with the Risk Control teams and ADM for break remediation planning and standards compliance.
- Design, deliver and maintain firm wide Privileged Access Management (PAM) solutions.
- Perform effective testing of inter-system connection and application controls.
- Worked extensively with data governance team to maintain data models, Metadata and dictionaries.
- Created and published multiple dashboards and reports using Tableau server.
- Extensively used SQL queries for legacy data retrieval jobs.
- Coordinating SOX walkthroughs for internal controls to ensure compliance with Sarbanes-Oxley legislation.
- Develop, maintain, and execute standard operating procedures (SOP) for all identity management.
- Coordinate on-going remediation efforts by working with stakeholders to determine ownership and appropriate corrective actions.
- Performed various walkthroughs and testing of entity-level controls, change controls, access controls, automated controls, process related controls, and other general controls such as disaster recovery, backups, and business continuity. Perform effective testing of inter-system connection and application controls.
- Build partnerships with business units to ensure that business requirements continually inform Role Based Access Control program
- Involve in testing & operations on various operating systems, databases and applications, including but not limited to SAP, PeopleSoft, Windows 2000 and Active Directory, AIX, UNIX, Mainframe, Oracle and proprietary technologies.

Business Analyst

Client: J P Morgan Chase

Jersey City, NJ

Employer: Axistech INC

Aug 2015 - June 2016

Project: BCBS Reporting (Auto Finance)

Worked for the Chase Auto Finance, BCBS (Basel Committee on Banking Supervision) Reporting project, specific responsibilities include producing project scope documents, documenting functional specifications, performing complex data analysis, data mapping, defining test scripts, liaising with the advisor end-users on business related project deliverables. Responsibilities include adherence to the defined SDLC processes, project deliverable management, advanced data analysis, issue and risk identification and tracking, as well as status reporting.

Responsibilities:

Facilitated collection of requirements from system users and preparation of business

requirement documents (BRD) using Requisite-Pro that provided appropriate scope of work for the technical teams.

- Developing Source to Target Mapping for the incoming data, certifying the quality of data in tables and files and also in getting the reporting requirement from business to incorporate it to SQL logic.
- Unwinding the existing logic in SQL Server/Oracle to fit into new ICDW model and create STT (Source to Target) documents
- Prepare a Base Query and the transformation logic for the respective target Integration Tables and Semantic views.
- Creating databases, users, tables, triggers, macros, views, stored procedures, functions, Packages, joins and hash indexes in Teradata database
- Performance analysis, monitoring and SQL query tuning using EXPLAIN PLAN, Collect Statistics, Hints and SQL Trace both in Teradata as well as Oracle
- Reviewing the referential and historical integrity of data warehouse information
- Coordinate with key stakeholders, subject matter experts, application owners, IT and other analysts for business requirements gathering and analysis.

Data Remediation Analyst

Client: First Hawaiian Bank Honolulu, HI Employer: Axistech INC Feb 2015 - July 2015

Project: CCAR (Financial Data Analysis)

Data Integration/Remediation project, for the Risk Analysis Division. My role was to access the information about the data source fields from the point of delivery mappings for the Banking systems and assess the impact on downstream data management environments of processing different banking products via different systems and processes. The banking systems included the Advanced Lending Solutions, Mortgage Servicing Systems, Mortgage Origination Systems, Collection & Recovery Systems, Automated Financial Systems and Total System Services.

Responsibilities:

- Profiling the CCAR Data fields in Enrich and source system fields.
- Verification of technical requirements for creating the CCAR fields in Oracle Database.
- Built and maintained SQL scripts, indexes, and complex queries for data analysis and extraction for varies projects.
- Analysis on the preliminary list of gaps and in scope systems/field to identify Data Modeling changes.
- Gathering the information about manual sources that are not captured in POD Mappings.
- Assisted in creating business requirements, technical specifications, implementation and test plans.
- Responsible to capture the Data Issues identified during: EY Assessment, Pod Documentation, profiling source system fields and Enrich Fields.

Software Engineer FRUX Software Solutions

AP, India Jun 2012 - July 2013

FRUX Software Solutions develops software solutions and provides integration services to deliver a standards-based, manageable and cost-effective infrastructure that reliably connects applications and integrated business processes across the extended platforms.

Responsibilities:

- Product development specializing in leading technologies like client-server, N-tier, E-Commerce, E-Governance and web-based applications.
- Maintenance and monitoring of Project wise performance of trainees, trainers, batch, training center and placement coordinators.

- Delivery of high-quality solutions in the field of Information Technology.
- Provide an objective system for recording and aggregating information.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- 'Python Programming Track' skill Track from DataCamp, ID 141198 in May-2020.
- *Certified Product Manager* International Organization for Project Management, ID 69101005446165 in Feb-2019.
- Certified Product Owner International Scrum Institute, ID 53429611817467 in Jan-2019.
- Certified Scrum Master International Scrum Institute, ID 28076394293457 in Jan-2019.
- Six Sigma Green Belt International Six Sigma Institute, ID 82059823175892 in Jan-2019.
- Six Sigma Yellow Belt Six Sigma Study, ID 679493 in Jan 2019.
- Certified Access Management Specialist Identity Management Institute, License 3944 in Feb-2018.
- Certified Identity and Access Manager Identity Management Institute, License 3676 in Jul-2017.
- *ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management* from EXIN ICT competence partner & AXELOS Global best practice, ID 5946432.20639998 in Mar-2017.
- 'The Language and Tools of Financial Analysis' Coursera Course Certificate, an online non-credit course authorized by University of Melbourne in Mar-2016.
- 'Financial Markets' Coursera Course Certificate, an online non-credit course authorized by Yale University in Feb-2016.
- **SAS Certified Base Programmer** for SAS 9 in Sep-2015.

EDUCATION

Columbus, OH

International MBA Institute

Jan 2019

- Master of Business Administration in Management.
- Coursework: Levels of Management; Management Skills; Approaches to Management; Management Planning

Oklahoma, OK, USA

Oklahoma State University

Sep 2013 - Dec 2014

- Master of Science in Electrical Engineering.
- Graduate Coursework: Digital Computer Design; Information Assurance Management; Digital System Testing; International Teaching Assistant Oral Proficiency; Linear Systems; Wireless Communications.

Visakhapatnam, AP, India

Gitam University

Jul 2008 - Apr 2012

- Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communication Engineering.
- Undergraduate Coursework: Database Management Systems; Web Technologies; Computer Architecture & Organization; Operating Systems; Wireless Communications & Networks; Electronics Measurements & Instrumentation.